regina.ca 2018-10-12

# Privacy - City of Regina

The City of Regina (the “City”) is committed to protecting personal, confidential and third party information.

All personal information collected by the City is done so in accordance with [_The Local Authority Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_. ](http://www.qp.gov.sk.ca/documents/English/Statutes/Statutes/L27-1.pdf)

City of Regina Privacy Policy

### What is personal information?

Personal information is defined as personal information about an identifiable individual that is recorded in any form. Personal information includes, but is not limited to: address; home telephone number; identifying numbers such as Social Insurance number, driver’s license number, Employee ID, Student ID; health information; employment history; criminal history; educational background; financial status/history; religion; personal opinions except when they are about another person; etc.

Personal information does not include business card information, classification, salary, benefits or expenses incurred while travelling at the expense of the City.

## What personal information does the City collect?

Some examples of personal information that the City may collect are:

  * Contact information such as name, address, phone number, business contact information or email address
  * Demographic information such as age, gender, education or household information
  * Health information
  * Identification information
  * Personal opinions
  * Financial information such as billing information, income information or service account information
  * Voice recording and video surveillance may be used to increase public safety and/or improve customer service. In such cases, the City will make every reasonable effort to ensure citizens are adequately informed.

## What does the City do with my personal information?

In most cases the personal information that we collect from you is used to deliver services on behalf of the City. For example, water service billing, fire protection services, recreation program registration, or responding to a customer inquiry.

  * Your personal information may be used to verify your identity or program eligibility.
  * From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices such as communications about utility billing and changes to our policies or terms of service. Because of your customer relationship with the City and because this information is important to your interaction with the City, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.
  * In some cases such as fire protection services, burial permit provision, or life guard response, the City may be required to collect personal information about the physical or mental condition of an individual.
  * Internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve the City’s services and communications
  * If you enter into a contest or similar promotion we may use the information you provide to administer those programs.
  * In some instances, subject to [Canada's Anti-Spam Legislation ](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/PDF/E-1.6.pdf), and to obtain the necessary consent, the personal information you provide such as email or mailing address may be used to contact you regarding new services available from the City, including upcoming events, facility information or other relevant notifications.
  * You may also be asked to provide your opinion or feedback on various topics from time to time. Participation in these types of initiatives is voluntary and an unsubscribe option will be provided should you wish to no longer receive correspondence related to that particular program or offering.

## Does the City of Regina collect or store personal information or track user behaviour?

  * Website users may consent, and voluntarily provide certain personal information (including but not limited to name, email address, phone number) to request services, enter contests, or complete online surveys.
  * Google Analytics may be used to collect and analyze statistics related to website use. No personally identifiable information is collected for this purpose.
  * All personal information is managed in accordance with  _The Local Authority Access to Information and Protection of Privacy Act_ as well as any other applicable Canadian and international privacy protection requirements, including Canada’s  _Anti-Spam Legislation_  and the  _European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)._
  * All information collected by the City is subject to Bylaw No. 2012-18  _The Records Retention and Disposal Schedules Bylaw, 2012._

## Is my information ever given to someone else?

We do not disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent unless disclosure is authorized by legislation, required by law or for the purposes of criminal investigation.

At times other government organizations such as SaskPower, SaskEnergy, Provincial Ministries, or Statistics Canada may require personal information or information verification from the City in order to register you for services, confirm eligibility or for statistical purposes. Any disclosure made to these agencies is done so in accordance with [_The Local Authority Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act._ ](http://www.qp.gov.sk.ca/documents/English/Statutes/Statutes/L27-1.pdf)

Your information may also be used or disclosed for the purpose of locating you in order to collect a debt you owe to the City or to make a payment owing to you by the City.

The Regina Fire & Protective Services Department may collect, use and disclose your medical information in the provision of emergency response services. In all services provided by the City where your personal health information is collected, including fire and protective services, it is only shared in legally authorized situations including providing medical information to EMS, external health care providers or authorized organizations.

The City does not sell or rent personal information to other organizations.

Your information may be disclosed to organizations contracted by the City to provide services on behalf of the City. Contractors must maintain and protect your information in accordance with Canadian and international privacy legislation.

In some cases, information may be stored outside of Canada and will be subject to the laws of that jurisdiction. Regardless of where information is stored, it must be maintained and protected in accordance with [_The Local Authority Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_. ](http://www.qp.gov.sk.ca/documents/English/Statutes/Statutes/L27-1.pdf)

### How is my personal information protected?

The City takes many precautions to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized collection, access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. These measures include various forms of physical, technical and administrative precautions.

_The Act_  protects personal information by restricting its collection, use and disclosure.

The City must only collect personal information that relates to the services provided by a municipality and the collection must be limited to information necessary for the provision of the service. The City has an obligation to inform the individual why the information is being collected and what it will be used for. The information must be used for the purpose for which it was collected or a use consistent with that purpose. Before the information is used for any other purpose, the City must obtain consent from the individual, preferably in writing.

_The Act_  provides for disclosure of personal information without consent in limited circumstances such as:

  * By subpoena or warrant
  * To legal counsel
  * To protect the mental or physical health or safety of an individual
  * To assist in the provision of services to the individual
  * To comply with an Act or regulation

There are security measures in place to protect personal information from unauthorized access or disclosure. For example: If a bylaw enforcement complaint is made, the City would ask for personal information such as name, address and telephone number of the caller in order to keep the individual informed about the handling of the complaint.  As a complainant, the personal information provided is protected and is not made public. The only time the identity of a complainant would be disclosed is to comply with court proceedings.

### How do I access my personal information at the City?

If you have questions about your personal information or would like access to your information please feel free to contact Service Regina at 306-777-7000.

If your request for information appears to require a disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, seems extremely impractical or if there is concern over whether or not the request is permitted by law, you may be directed to make an Access to Information Request. Information regarding access to information process at the City of Regina as well as a downloadable application form is available on our website or by [email](mailto:LAFOIP@regina.ca).

### How do I make sure my information is accurate and how long does the City keep my information?

The City relies on your assistance to help maintain the accuracy and completeness of your personal information. Your information is retained for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

You can help ensure that your contact information is accurate, complete, and up to date by contacting Service Regina at 306-777-7000 or by using the [Contact Us form ](https://www.regina.ca/site/contact/online-request-form/index.html).

### How do I make changes to my personal information?

The City must take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information in its possession is accurate and complete, but it is also an individual’s responsibility to ensure that the City is informed of changes in personal information.

If the information is inaccurate or incomplete, contact:

  * Information Services Corporation (ISC) for tax notices and change of ownership; and
  * Saskatchewan Government Insurance (SGI) for parking tickets and summons

For any other changes to personal information, contact Service Regina at 306-777-7000.

### How do I make a privacy complaint?

If you believe that the City of Regina has mishandled your personal information or has not adequately responded to your request for access to your personal information please complete the Privacy Complaint Form  and mail it to:

City of Regina Access Privacy Team  
C/o Office of the City Clerk  
PO Box 1790  
Regina, SK S4P 3C8  
Email: [lafoip@regina.ca](mailto:lafoip@regina.ca).

## Links

Our website may contain links to other websites which are provided to you as a convenience only. You are advised that other third party websites may have different privacy practices than the City of Regina. The City has no responsibility for such third party websites.

Photos on www.regina.ca supplied by Tourism Regina, Regina Leader Post, Regina Downtown Business Improvement District, Saskatchewan Tourism, Patricia Holdsworth, and City of Regina employees.
